Kyle Romero

 ♥ Jersey City, NJ
 ■ kgromero@gmail.com
 □ (281) 857-9006
 Im in/kyleromero
 ▲ kgromero.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineering Leader with 10 years as a full-stack developer and 7 years in management, living in the NYC Metro Area. Looking for the next opportunity to lead a development organization to success, maximize business value, and provide great user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Software Development

Raymour & Flanigan

March 2023 - May 2024, Jersey City, NJ (remote)

- · Largest Initiatives: ERP Migration to NetSuite, WMS Migration to Korber, Omnichannel Sales Experience via E-Commerce Site, 3rd Party API Integrations (ChargeAfter, Bringg).
- Team Size: 3 Managers (.NET Team, Oracle Team, Boomi Team), 4 Architects, 30 Developers (mix of internal and near/off shore resources).
- Primary Tech Stack: .NET (C#, UWP, ASP.NET Core), SQL Server, Oracle DB, Azure, AWS, React, Git, PowerBI, Windows Server, Boomi, Snowflake.
- Defined and executed organizational strategy, including transformational 5 year vision.
- Negotiated, reviewed, and managed development partner (near-shore / on-shore) and vendor contracts / resources, which reduced contract costs by 40%.
- Forecasted and controlled organizational budget and credit card, reducing costs by 25%.
- Directly led change control and release management processes, leading to 50% decrease in production defect rate.
- · Aligned cross-functional teams within internal matrixed organization and operated as SME alongside architects (direct reports) to define and executive organizational architecture strategy.
- · Coordinated with infrastructure team to monitor and control cloud and on-premises costs.

Manager of Software Development

MEARS Group

October 2017 - March 2023, Jersey City, NJ (remote)

- Mission-Critical Projects: Mission Critical SOX-compliant internally developed Revenue/Time/Equipment Field Capture solution, used by over 700 field construction crews across the US. This solution sped up the closing process by 75%. Electron based Field Safety Capture application with online/offline capability that digitized all safety documentation field crews must capture
- Team Size: 4 Developers, 1 PM, 7 Offshore (100% remote team).
- Primary Tech Stack: .NET (C#, ASP.NET Core), SQL Server, Sqlite3, Azure / Windows Server, JavaScript (Angular / React / Node / Electron), Git, PowerBI, PowerAutomate, Java (Spring Boot).
- · Reported directly to CIO and focused on digital transformation and continuous improvement, including participating in Six Sigma and Kaizen initiatives.
- Traveled to U.S. locations to roll out applications and lead Change Management (25% travel).
- · Implemented and trained organization on DevOps/CICD, Agile Scrum, Kanban, GitFlow, and QA processes, which increased delivery speed by 50%.
- Onboarded and coordinated offshore development partner based out of India.
- Nominated to Innovator Group and Quanta Leadership Academy 2.

Team Lead

Worldwide Machinery

April 2016 - October 2017, Houston, TX

- · Led internal software development team and reported to co-owner of company.
- Full-stack development using .NET, MS SQL, and React which delivered mission-critical asset management software (desktop, mobile, and web) that managed \$300mil worth of heavy machinery assets.
- Built mobile-first SPA to enable employees to utilize real-time telemetrics on machinery assets.

Technical Lead

HP Inc.

December 2011 - February 2016, Houston, TX

- Designated as technical lead over mission-critical third level support tool with 10k+ global users.
- Full-stack development delivering 3-tier web applications using .NET, MS SQL, and JavaScript.
- Gained exposure to big data (Hadoop / HP Vertica) and BI/analytics (PowerBI / Tableau).
- $\bullet\,$ Led logical split and cloning of system during HP's split into HPE and HP Inc..
- Promoted Once (Senior Developer \rightarrow Technical Lead).

Software Developer

X-Fab Texas

August 2007 - December 2011, Lubbock, TX

- Full-Stack developer specializing in .NET, MS SQL, C++, and Perl development (Windows and Linux).
- · Built 3-tier web applications and hardware monitoring solutions and introduced Subversion source control to company.
- Deployed distributed databases and web applications in the U.S., Germany, and Malaysia.

Software Development Intern

Texas Tech / X-Fab Texas

May 2007 - July 2007, Lubbock, TX

- Full-stack development internship with emphasis on C++ and .NET development.
- Completed a statistical analysis application and a file format conversion program.
- $\bullet \ \, {\sf Successfully presented internship results to Texas Tech University internship board.}$

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Texas Tech University • Lubbock, TX • 2009

• Covered Computer Science and Electrical Engineering Topics